Travers La Ville

Address: 7201 Wood Hollow dr Austin, Tx 78731

Website: lavillesolutions.com Email: traverslaville@gmail.com Phone: (832) 917- 8602

MISSION STATEMENT

Hard-working, self-motivated, creative looking for an enriching Entry Level Web Developer position to support a team in implementing bar-none user interaction following client-approved mock-ups, such as wireframes, visual design comprehensive layouts, and prototypes. Bringing a keen eye for details, strong ability to implement mock-ups, and understanding of great user experience design; three years experience in visual UI / front-end development work, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery and XHTML 1.1, Web Standard HTML5 and over 4 years of client service experience.

SKILLS

Technologies: php, oracle, html, css, javascript/jquery, ajax, mysql, MS access, codeigniter, Bootstrap,

Software: unix, windows, putty, vs code, filezilla, vm box, git bash, netbeans, gimp, microsoft office suite,

tiny take

Platforms: peoplesoft, drupal, wordpress, slack, hostgator, digitalocean,

Analytics and Reporting: Analytical reports, technical papers, contracts, technical requirements documents, vision and

spec documents, test plans, web forms, web reports, ad-hoc reports, executive summaries

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Brandmuscle, Inc.

Client Services Representative - Farmers Insurance Group

2014 - 2017

- Maintaining client / business-to-business relationships via client meetings and conference calls
- Responsible for resolving financial data discrepancies above \$1 million threshold for ongoing projects
- Responsible for quarterly project scheduling and budget establishment and adherence
- Coordinate staffing needs for project support while adhering to project launch schedules

Project Lead, Marketing Reporting Suite - Farmers Insurance Group

- Negotiated project schedule and budget with Program Director of Farmers
- Designed and tested 260 hours worth of project design work to enable a end-user reporting tool
- Formulated comprehensive test plans to implement reporting tool in adherence of launch schedule
- Managed products on client site with enriched meta-data for optimal UX, HTML, CSS and DNS event log monitoring

Business Analyst, Account Reconciliation - Farmers Insurance Group

- Developed over 50 complex analytical queries in SQL to create graphic dashboards and reporting for the client to visualize their data in a meaningful way and solve discrepancies between data and web reporting
- Resolved payment discrepancies and transactional disputes valued over \$300k
- Analyzed invoicing process for North America to ident
- Managed weekly meetings with team members across time zones and offices to coordinate projects and reconcile sales data issues

Just Brakes

Manager/ Service Writer

2013- 2014

- Managed price-points for both the company and customer in accordance with corporate guidelines
- Recovered over 20k in accounts receivable per month
- Developed corporate SOP regarding legal liability for services provided
- Maintained customer appointment schedule to ensure a timely customer experience

Coordinated inter-office communication regarding sales campaigns and promotional offers

Connectivity Source

Service Technician Manager

2009 - 2013

2

- Improved a third-quintile location to a first-quintile store in under two months
- Collaborated with more than 8 insurance companies to process approximately 1,000 cell phone claims per month
- Created training procedures to onboard more than 20 additional employees

Service Technician

- Promoted to Service Technician Manager after 6 weeks
- Maintained accurate billing records to process insurance claims
- Received Sprint Service Technician certification

La Ville Solutions Present

Owner

- Manufactured a more dynamic web experience for Austin based businesses and artists by leveraging web languages various solutioning tools
- Consulted

EDUCATION

Concordia University, Austin, TX *Bachelor of Science - Computer Science*

Present